Cesare Riverso

M: 956-890-1903

E: Riversocesare@yahoo.com W: https://italoriverso.com/

Summary

Well-qualified Full Stack Web Developer/Graphic Designer familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Able to handle any part of the process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering years of related experience.

Experience

Sr Designer, Italo Marketing – 2016-Present

- Deliver production ready graphics in HTML and CSS for all marketing assets.
- Research current and emerging art and graphic design technologies.
- Generate computer graphics and page-layout software, graphic elements and photography.
- Design website layouts, templates and unique branded looks.
- Meet with customers to present mockups and collect information for adjustments.
- Hands-on experience using UNIX and Apache web servers.
- Implement Google Campaigns and SEO for various types of websites.
- Convert mockups into HTML, JavaScript, AJAX and JSON.
- Utilize programming capabilities in PHP, SQL and JavaScript and other libraries as needed.
- Create wireframes, screen-flow diagrams and UI spec documentation.

Adobe Illustrator Instructor Bootcamp-Code Rgv- 2018-2018

- Adapted teaching methods and materials to meet students' varying needs and interests.
- Consistently received positive teacher evaluations from students.
- Took ideas and developed high quality creations, which included characters, environments and other objects.
- Trained designers on computer graphic design programs such as , Adobe Illustrator and Adobe Photoshop.

Marketing Manager Kidiatric Therapy Services – 2010-2014

- Developed innovative and targeted collateral to support overall branding objectives.
- Retained clients to build brand awareness and generate leads while managing internal and external marketing campaigns and programs.

Certification

Full stack Developer

Graduation Date

2018

- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement in a fast-paced environment.
- Provided continued maintenance and development of bug fixes and patch sets for existing web applications.
- Formatted text and graphics for blog posts, newsletters and other materials.

Valley Technical Academy

School/Organization

Maintained consistent use of graphic imagery in materials and other marketing outreach.

	Comptia	A+ Certification	2017				
	Code RGV	Python Certification	2017				
	University Of the People	Information Technology	2020				
Technical Competencies							
Project management	Website optimization	Web site advertising	• MySQL				
Production layouts	 Web development projects 	 Flier and poster printing 	• PHP				
 Logo design 	Web platform developmentWebsite maintenance	Linux Photoshop	 JavaScript 				
Web user interfaces			 WordPress 				
Agile workflow processes		 Illustrator 	 Shopify 				
	 Photography 	• HTML5	ASP.NET				
 Team oversight 	experience	• CSS3	 Jquery 				
 Customer service 	Branding strategiesWebsite graphics						
Email management software		 Angular2+ 	• Linux				
		TypeScript					

languages

Education

English, Italian, Spanish, and Chinese

·		